

☐ request with a message | ► hi@alpcoker.com | ♣ alpcoker.com | ☐ alpcoker | ☐ alpcoker

Bio - Background

I'm a software craftsperson who loves to be in the center of creating software that is providing value for humanity or makes companies make great profits or makes them efficient. I always think about creating an impact on existing circumstances. I identify myself as a problem solver who is not a specific tech fanatic. I apply the most optimum solution when and where necessary.

I have thirteen years of experience and worked for seven companies from start-ups to big enterprise companies. I have worked in the following industries; energy, cryptocurrency, travel, defense, mission-critical, government, and geographic information systems. I have worked on-site, remote and cross continent company environments. I have both experience in synchronous and asynchronous development environments.

I have two open-source projects that I love to work. As an achievement, I have one first place and two degrees in competitions for professionals.

Career Objectives

I love to work with the best of my skills for getting our(my) project to reach its goals. I will be satisfied if my output is used by other people and it is completing our goals one by one. I always try to put my best effort to reach desired quality for any kind of work in our remaining time.

I always try/want to be (stay as) an innovative and target-driven engineer. I seek better solutions, and best practices not just in my career, but also apply them to my life. I look for new challenges, goals, and responsibilities that can keep me active and fresh in my life. While I am working with my colleagues, I always try to move/develop/focus together. Because there can't be only a single human behind any big successes.

Experience _____

Tesla - Electric Cars, Solar & Clean Energy

Amsterdam, Netherlands

SENIOR FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2023 - ongoing

- I am working in the IT Applications department which is located across the United States, Netherlands & China. Tesla develops in-house solutions for their processes. I have responsibilities in the whole process of one of the internal applications used within the company. *Confidential*
- · Used technologies: .NET 3.1 .NET 7, Angular, MySQL, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Elastic Stack, Redis, Jenkins, GitHub Enterprise, Atlassian Products

BtcTurk - Cryptocurrency Exchange & Platform - Highest Cryptocurrency Volume in Turkey

Remote, Turkey

SENIOR BACK-END SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2022 - Jun. 2022

- I worked on the cash flow team. I was responsible for fiat deposits and withdrawals on a cryptocurrency exchange which has a very high market value. The platform was using a microservices architecture. I was developing and monitoring the system's health.
- · Used technologies: .NET 6, RabbitMQ, Microsoft SQL Server, Azure, Elastic Stack, Redis, Atlassian Products

Otelz - Online Travel Agency - Most Popular in Turkey

Remote, Turkey

SENIOR FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mar. 2021 - Feb. 2022

- I developed Expedia integration to enable the company to expand abroad. Company can list hotels not just in Turkey but in the world. This includes data synchronization between companies' different models, searching, listing hotel availability, making payments and, reservations.
- I developed a new channel manager (a system for hotels to manage their availability in real-time) integration that is widely used by big resorts. For our existing channel manager integrations with a count of 25, I maintained and monitored them.
- · Used technologies: .NET 5, React, Microsoft SQL Server, Azure DevOps, Elastic Stack, AWS, Redis, Atlassian Products

T2 🗗 - Defence Industry Ankara, Turkey

SENIOR FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- $\bullet \ \ \mathsf{I} \ \mathsf{redesigned} \ \mathsf{the} \ \mathsf{architecture} \ \mathsf{of} \ \mathsf{their} \ \mathsf{mission} \ \mathsf{critical} \ \mathsf{desktop} \ \mathsf{systems} \ \mathsf{to} \ \mathsf{their} \ \mathsf{intranet} \ \mathsf{web} \ \mathsf{environment}.$
- Used technologies: React, Java 11, Spring, Kotlin, TimescaleDB with PostgreSQL, Elastic Stack, GitLab Enterprise

Havelsan 🗹 - Defence Industry - Reference: Hülya Vural - Software Engineering Manager 🗗

Ankara, Turkey

SENIOR FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER & ARCHITECT

May 2017 - Aug. 2020

- I was designing architecture, defining development standards, fixing performance issues, security flaws, new framework features.
- Used technologies: ASP.NET Core 3.1, ASP.NET MVC, Angular, Oracle Database, Elastic Stack, Redis, Team Foundation Server

BilgeAdam 🗹 - Outsourcing for Government Offices - Reference: Seçkin Bedük - Software Development Director 🗷

Ankara, Turkey

SENIOR FULL-STACK SOFTWARE CONSULTANT

Aug. 2014 - May 2017

- I replaced a high traffic government public service with a new modern architecture to solve previous maintenance difficulties.
- $\bullet \quad \text{Used technologies: Windows Presentation Foundation, ASP.NET Core, SQL Server, SQL Server Integration Services, Team Foundation Server} \\$

Başarsoft 🗗 - Geographic Information System Company - Reference: Emrah Yılmaz - R&D Manager ♂

Ankara, Turkey

JUNIOR MOBILE & SERVICES R&D SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2010 - Jan. 2014

• I developed Windows CE, Windows Mobile, tablet applications which are connected and navigation systems customized by customer needs.

Used technologies: .NET Compact Framework, ASP.NET Web Services, SQL Server, Oracle, TCP/IP, ASP.NET, Team Foundation Server.

OSS - Open Source Software

.NET **photo-cli**, Extract when and where (reverse geocoding) your photos are taken, copy into a new organized folder with various folder & file naming strategies, export into CSV files.

photo-cli 🖸

.NET **PackBlock**, .NET & React toolchain for developers to rapidly develop customizable and extensible web applications. Private repo, need invitation.

PackBlock 🖸

Skills (w/years of experience)_

Languages C# (13), JavaScript(8), Typescript(4), Python(2), Golang(1), Kotlin(1), Java(1), R(1)

Technologies

NET(13), ASP.NET(10), React(4), Angular(2), Vue.js(1), HTTP-REST API(9), OAuth-OIDC(2), WPF(4), Windows Forms(3), Spring

Boot(1), Hadoop(1), Spark(1), HTML(9), CSS(5)

Architecture Microservices(5), Message Broker(4), Hexagonal(2), Miniservices(2), CQS & CQRS(2), Monolithic(9), Layered & n-tier(8), MVC(3),

Service-Oriented Architecture(4), Modular(4), Client-Server(2), Outbox(1), TDD(1), Strangler(1), API Composition(1)

SDLC Rapid application development(5), Kanban(3), Scrum(2), Extreme Programming(2), Spiral Model(1)

Database MS-SQL Server(10), PostgreSQL(7), Elastic Search(6), Redis(6), Oracle(4), MongoDB(3), Prometheus(2), MySQL(1), HBase(1)

Platforms Kibana(6), RabbitMQ(2), Kafka(2), Grafana(2), Kubernetes(1), Fluentd(1), Camunda Workflow(1), Jaeger(1)

Azure DevOps-TFS(8), Docker(6), Linux(7), Git(5), GitHub(4), AWS(2), Azure(1), Heroku(1), GitLab(2), Atlassian(2), NGINX(2), NPM(1), DevOps

Jenkins(2)

Tools Rider(7), WebStorm(5), PyCharm(3), DataGrip(5), VS Code(4), Linux(10), Windows(20), macOS(2), Visual Studio(10), Postman(6)

Achievements

Third place with our team, Havelsan Hackathon 2020
 Finalist with our team, Microsoft Imagine Cup 2010

Ankara, Turkey Istanbul, Turkey

Competition WinnerIstanbul, Turkey

MICROSOFT & TURKCELL May. 2009

• I have participated and won first place in a Mobile Application Development Competition which was hosted by Microsoft Turkey and Turkcell (the biggest mobile operator company in Turkey). My application is a social network for Windows Mobile users. With this application users create places and fill it's profile to be search by others. They can also share and tweet their locations within the application. This application very similar to Foursquare/Swarm but I have developed them they have published.

Education

2015

2015

Introduction to R 🖒 , DataCamp

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

2010-2013 **Master of Science in Computer Engineering**, Çankaya University (GPA 3,6 over 4) 2006-2010 **Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering**, Çankaya University (GPA 3,2 over 4)

Ankara, Turkey Ankara, Turkey

DataCamp

edX

Certifications

2018	M001: MongoDB Basics 🕘, M101P: MongoDB for Developers 🕘, M201: MongoDB Performance 🕘 ,	MongoDB University	
	MongoDB University	Mongoob Oniversity	
2016	The Data Scientist's Toolbox, 🖒 , R Programming 🖒 , Getting and Cleaning Data 🖒 ,	Coursera	
	Exploratory Data Analysis 🕘 , Reproducible Research 🕘 , Johns Hopkins University		
2016	Graph Analytics for Big Data 🕘 , Hadoop Platform and Application Framework 🕘 ,		
	Introduction to Big Data Analytics 🕘 , Introduction to Big Data 🕘 , Machine Learning With Big Data	Coursera	
	但, University of California, San Diego		
2016	Machine Learning: Regression 2 , Machine Learning: Classification 2 ,	Coursera	
	Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach (2), University of Washington		
2016	Advanced Techniques for Designing HTML5 Apps 🕘, HTML5 Coding Essentials and Best Practices 😩	edX	
	World Wide Web Consortium (W3C)		
2015	Data Structures and Algorithms 4, Algorithmic Toolbox 4, University of California, San Diego	Coursera	

Computational Thinking and Data Science 🕘 , Computer Science and Programming Using Python 🕘 ,